The modern corporation as we know it was first formed in 1602
现代公司最初形成于1602年
with the government chartered Dutch East India Company.
由政府许可的荷兰东印度公司
This is kind of the first modern corporation with shareholders and organizations
可能是第一个有组织的股份制公司
that kind of if you squinted looked like something closed to modern companies today.
仔细来看，它很像如今的公司
By the 1850s in the United States with railroads spanning the entire country,
在19世纪50年代，铁路网络纵横美国南北
corporations needed more sophisticated organizations
公司需要变成更复杂的结构
and the fact the first org chart was drawn in 1856 to just manage corporations
一个事实是第一个便于管理公司的组织结构图绘成于1856年
and by the beginning of the 20th century, educators started realizing
到20世纪初期，教育者开始认识到
that there was a need for an educated management class to administer and execute these corporations
有必要设置教授公司管理和执行的专业管理课程
because at least in the United States we were going from local economies to regional economies
因为至少在美国，我们从地方经济发展为区域经济
to a national economy, yet we did not have a trained management class
再到国民经济，其间我们却缺乏良好的管理课程
and so in a brilliant insight, Harvard set up the first masters of business administration course
对此，有着慧眼的哈佛大学，开设了世上第一个工商管理硕士专业课程
called the MBA and the first graduating class in 1910 was the first of a
简称MBA，在1910年，它的第一批毕业生诞生
cadre of business administrators that made the 20th century the modern corporate century.
他们成为商业管理领域的中流砥柱，成就了20世纪，一个现代公司的世纪
The MBA curriculum is designed to provide managers and administrators
MBA课程大纲设计为向管理者们
with the tools they needed to run existing and growing companies.
提供业已存在的和发展中的公司所需的工具
Accounting, strategy, operations, leadership, organizational behavior,
财会、战略、运营，领导力、组织行为、人力资源管理
human resources management and these stack of tools were just incredibly important
这些工具对于大型公司的发展
for the growth of large companies but what's really interesting what that missed is that
起着异常重要的作用，然而有趣的是，课程大纲缺失的
they were really no tools provided in this curriculum for starting new businesses.
是为创业公司提供工具
One of the things we did not understand for 100 years
我们一百年来都没弄明白的一点是
is that startups are not smaller versions of large companies.
创业公司不是缩小的大公司
Let me say it again--startups are not smaller versions of large companies
再强调一遍：创业公司不是麻雀虽小五脏俱全的公司
and what falls out of that is all the traditional tools taught and learned in an MBA curriculum
事实上，在所有MBA课程里学到的传统工具
are irrelevant in the first chaotic year or two of an early stage venture.
在混乱的创业早期的头一两年里起不到一点作用
Eventually, you need that tool set but at first it really gets in the way.
最终你需要这些工具，但在创业早期，它们只会阻碍你